cers there's a whole conversation that
was happening in the Discord that's like
we need a better name for us than
CTS like cers yeah we're all from
Connecticut yeah we're all like C tier
hackers we're all C tier hackers yeah
[Music]
hey guys real quick I just wanted to
tell you about our sponsor threat Locker
now wait wait before you hit this skip
forward button let me just say this most
of the stuff that holds my attention
nowadays is red team stuff as well but I
sat down with the threat Locker team
this past week to do a demo of their EDR
software and it was super technically
fascinating how this thing works so
check this out you drop this thing on a
system right and for the first week or
so it's creating a policy and a profile
for that system it's logging all the
executables uh what child processes are
being spawned uh the files and their
hashes that sort of thing and it's
creating this policy okay then after the
learning mode is up we're in secured
mode and that policy gets put into place
and anything that's not on that allow
list is immediately autod denied that's
the zero trust piece right so in
addition to that they've got a bunch of
crazy features like ring fencing and
dynamic access controls that would stop
a malicious hacker at pretty much every
step along the way actually I I was
watching this demo and I was kind of
freaked out because I have no idea how I
would cope with getting dropped into a
threat locker system as a red teamer
anyway if you want to learn more about
this head over to threat locker.com and
request a demo and when you do ask for
my boy Andrew his demo was super to the
point and he was able to answer all my
technical questions all right cool back
to the
show
PL
PL you hear that Joel you hear that
that's a brainstorm coming that is the
rain uh wow that
was are we GNA keep
that dude Justin like hyped this up he's
like dude I got the best intro like wait
till you hear this wait till you hear
this okay go you know cuz but it's like
I was I made the voice you know I did
the sound with my mouth you know for the
brain draining you know and then it's a
brain storm you see what I'm saying I
thought we were talking about toilets
again in the beginning I'm no no no no
we're not doing it we're not doing
it all right dude ready for a brainstorm
episode uh I guess so yeah dude I um I
was uh did you have thunderstorms
yesterday because we had we had
thunderstorms I thought that's why you
you brought that up no no my house is
not leaking everything is good I just
you know the amount of valuable
information that is just raining out of
our brains right now it just needed to
be vocalized
yes all right well thanks for bearing
with me there Joel for that um so we're
GNA brainstorm today on um various types
of plugins extensions Chrome extensions
kaido extensions burp extensions man
inthe middle proxy extensions all these
sort of things um but before we get to
that man Gareth Hayes just tweeted
something out dude and you know when
Gareth Hayes tweets something out your
boy is on it like her in a gorilla so I
he's one of the few people who have
tweet notifications turn on for yeah uh
along with the critical thinking podcast
critical critical
critical oh man we've getting a little
goofy lately we got
this uh okay but anyways I like went I
sat down on the toilet
and and I pulled my phone out and sure
enough I have all these tweet
notifications from Gareth haes and uh
he's tweeted some crazy big
brain uh I don't even know what is this
a zero day weird Behavior so okay so let
me let me clarify on this because I I
saw this and I was like wait what the
heck this is super weird I hadn't even
understood this and and then like Yan
Carlson Pops in there and he's like H
this is like kind of cool but pretty
normal but let me add some context to
this okay so um the tweet that Gareth
tweeted out that we're talking about is
essentially just an a tag that he
tweeted out and the a Tag's HRA is a
slash and then ERS Sam
Bol uh semicolon right so it's a HTML
entity Bol which apparently is for
backslash I don't know why it's Bol um
and then he uses like a like a negative
medium space um uh entity as well HTML
entity and then uh you know provides
shazard .co.uk as the domain where this
uh HF should be going to and when you
click on this link it goes to chazzer um
and it doesn't start with SL slash um
and and so like here's the thing with
this is like there's always so many
times we've talked about it time and
time again on the Pod where you're
trying to fuzz for a way to get around
um a redirect URI or something like that
in an oo flow or um get the some some
like if frame uh Source attribute to
like point to a different host rather
than a a relative URL within the host
right um and I think this is just
another great way to get around it and
somehow I just hadn't fully formulated
in my brain that we can use HTML
entities inside of uh these HTML
attributes like this and especially you
know with the research that came out
from the RC man that we covered on the
Pod a long time ago um about like the
different types of HTML entities that
have kind of been overlooked and and
Shazer um you know whipped up a whole
list of all these crazy HTML entities
that we hadn't heard of before um this
is just becoming more important in my
brain is like okay how can we utilize
these sort of under under served
undern HTML entities to break out of
these various contexts um inside of an
HTML attribute um and I think that's
exactly what what he does here yeah yeah
for sure um I just posted uh a link in
the doc we we'll include it in the in
the references but uh Wikipedia actually
has a really good table uh I found that
has like just a list of all the XL and
HTML um character entities jeez there's
a ton dude I did not know there's a ton
there's a ton um of like really weird
ones including like you know special
characters and all sorts of stuff like
soul and back Soul B Soul like you uh
like you said um there's also like
fraction slash so maybe
like R ASL so maybe that would get um
normalized somewhere somehow um yeah so
there's there's a lot of really
interesting um interesting stuff yeah
that fraction slash is a is not um
Unicode Cod Point
z2f that's Unicode code Point 2044 so
that's like a like a a
non yeah a non asky uh character there
um so man there's a lot of really
interesting stuff stuff here I I think
man there's just so many dude I'm like
scrolling and scrolling and scrolling on
how many entities there are here and I'm
sure there's going to be a bunch of
other bugs relating to this but the the
attack factor that came to my mind and
came to the mind of um uh Haku piku in
the reverse order there right like when
I saw it I was like oh man this is going
to be really helpful in redirects and
then like uh 10 minutes later uh hakuu
uh messages me and he's like hey man
this is really helpful in ooth flows um
because what you can do is you can set
the response type to form post right and
the way that that works is then it'll
generate an HTML element so if you have
an ooth flow that's going to um uh
return a code or whatever like normal
oath does if you set the response type
to form post instead of like 302ing what
it'll do is generate a HTML page with a
with a form and it's going to set the
action on that form to be whatever your
redirect URL is so if you're able to
specify a relative URL you know and
they're saying all right as long as it
starts with Slash and it doesn't you
know have a backs slash or a forward
slash next to it um then we're fine then
you can use this sort of entity this uh
Ampersand Bou semicolon um to bypass
that flow and actually redirect to an
absolute URL or I guess more
specifically a protocol relative URL um
and then leak that code out to
uh another domain that isn't within that
redirect URI flow so my my prediction
and I think Haku
P's um prediction as well is that this
will affect a lot of uh oath flows
specifically in the the form post
environment yeah yeah this is really
interesting and uh I don't want to spoil
too too much but I I have a I have a
thought that I see has already been
thought ahead of my thought so um about
something related to this uh what is
what is your you're just not going to
say it on the an extension idea oh
really okay there you go all right it's
something that's in the list too it's
already in the list it is in the list I
did put that in the list I was like this
would be a good idea and then I went and
I looked and I was like this is already
thing so yeah um we we'll talk about it
later but okay yeah now that sounds that
sounds great um very cool stuff there
tldr of that whole situation there's a
bunch of we weird weird HTML attributes
out or HTML entities uh out there you
should know them and definitely check
out check out the um the Shazer results
for all the fuzzing of HDML entities
that that Garrett's been doing because
lots of weird stuff is coming out of
that um all right what's this next one
on the list Joel there's a there's a
there's a link on the list from from
Joel from me from me this is
revolutionary okay so um Chris Evans who
uh is the uh the ceso
um over at hacker one mhm tweeted out
that they are making a change to the
hacker one leaderboard and now hacker
leaderboards are
separated based on bug Bounty program
reputation vulnerability disclosure
program reputation and then both
together and by default it shows just
the buck Bounty program reputation in
the leaderboard so now VPS uh you're if
you're farming on bdps that's not going
to boost you in the default
leaderboard it will boost you in the
separate and combined leaderboards for
vdps and both but the default
leaderboard is the bug Bounty program
leaderboard that's where you're going to
have the most reputation I like I like
that they broke it out and then I like
that they made uh bug binding program
the default and I wonder how this is
going to show up on your profile as well
because I think you know the hacker one
leaderboards is great for essentially us
PE us folks that are really in the
hacker one environment and we like go
there and we want to compete and we want
to see where we're at and that sort of
thing but I think for a lot of people um
the profile is the bigger measure like
being able to have you know hacker
one.com rerer you go there you see oh
Justin's you know I don't know this
month I'm probably like not even in the
top 100 or whatever because I've been
doing so much things for the critical
thinkers um uh but you know like that
view that's in the on the profile I
think is going to be super duper
important like what is being highlighted
there and what metric says okay in the
last 90 days Justin is uh you know in
the top 50 or whatever as far as a bug
Bounty reputation goes yeah yeah and I
think I may have said that it already is
that they already made the change it's
planned I don't know when it's planning
on being rolled out this was just
tweeted
um less than 24 hours ago yesterday so
yeah it's uh it's still I don't know but
there's a screen got so they're
definitely like engineering it to some
extent it's probably going to come out
within the next couple weeks so um
pretty soon well this is you know this
is the result of that whole conversation
that started uh a while back uh with
nogly I think tweeting something out and
starting a fire like he always does um
and yeah so it's good to see that them
them actually following through on this
and then and then uh it also just shows
like how long it takes to get like a
markup of uh of what this UI chain
should look like in these biger
organization sometimes man and uh you
know that's the world of uh software
engineering I I always think things
should take less Long than they do but
it is what it is yeah you never know you
never know it's always it's always
impossible to plan these things properly
yeah for sure all righty man cool well
let's get into the storm let the
lightning let the lightning let the
Thunder begin it's cracking yeah exactly
let's start let's start brain storing
Okay so I'll start out with a couple and
then you like in true in true Joel style
we can you know you can just take those
ideas and make them better and bounce
off fit okay sure so um first first one
that I wanted to talk about uh is I
think
that a 403 bypassing workflow in kaido
is something that I really want to want
to work on and here and obviously I know
that that there's a um that there's a
403 bypasser plugin in burp Suite okay
um and if you look at that plugin it
does you know it shows all these like
path rsal things that it will do and it
tries it lists like maybe eight things
that it will try in there and um here's
the problem with that is I feel like
this needs to be custom for each person
because I there's a ton of tricks that I
know that are not in this uh 4 or3
bypasser extension right and if I have
this 403 bypasser extension I'm going to
see a 403 and I'm going to right click
on it I'm going to say trigger the the
403 bypasser extension
and then it's going to do its thing and
then I'm going to assume that it tried
the things and it's not so this is one
of the things that I really like about
about kaido is like um for one there's a
lot of ground that kaido has to make up
uh on on the plug-in space and and we're
moving towards it we're we're we're
knocking it out um it'll be there
probably within the next year or so but
um I think that one of the areas where
it shines is this whole concept of
custom automation right not not
everybody has the time to go break out
their Java environment and build their
own custom burp plugins that are like
super hard to write and you're using
this language and it's just G whereas
with kaido you've got the the low code
noode interface for automation you can
easily say okay hey I want to take the
request I want to sub uh I want to do
URL encoding on the last uh portion of
the of the path right and I want to
resend that request and I want an alert
if that response is different than the
response that I send without URL
encoding that right this classic 403
bypasser bypassing technique right so I
think there's a lot of Merit to having
your own 403 bypassing methodology
automated and implemented in a workflow
or if you you are a diard burp fan in
your own burp extension um because those
things that you know about how to bypass
43s or that you have experience with
about how to get around a certain
control that That's What Makes You
unique as a hacker and that's what you
need to automate yeah yeah for sure I
yeah I think um generally speaking
there's a lot of plugins that need to be
ported over and we're there's a couple
that we're going to talk about
specifically yeah um so that are like
really great plugins that should be
ported over um and I think probably some
of them might be able to be made work a
lot easier like kaido you can call Shell
commands so if you really want and it's
python which a lot of them are for to
work with jython like you could just
take the core functionality of that
plugin put it in a separate python file
call it out directly from kaido in a
workflow and just you know call it a day
don't bother makeing any more
complicated than that um but I think
some are definitely a little more
complicated than that and a lot more
involved or they have UI components and
stuff like that that need to be
converted over um but once those things
can be ported over it's going to be huge
yeah and don't know that I mention this
to you but there's a probably by the
time this episode airs um the basic
implementation of backend plugins for
kaida will be in place which will open
up the the possibilities for creating
things like otter eyes and um uh like um
turbo Intruder and and all these sort of
uh like a single packet attack based
thing right um all of these sort of key
features of of burp um will be able to
be ported over here shortly and I'm
really looking forward to that and I
think that's that's great and I think it
also creates an opportunity for us to
look at these plugins that we've been
trusting for years and years and years
and say okay I've used this Tool Time
and Time Again where are my pain points
and and let me make this better when I
transition it over to kaido you know or
or when I transition it over to like a
man- in the- Middle proxy extension like
we were talking about where if you want
to write something that is independent
of kaido or independent of burp right
then maybe men in the middle proxy might
be the right solution where you can just
kind of chain these things together and
it's a very lightweight intermediate
that doesn't cost anything um so yeah I
think there's a lot of a lot of ground
to cover up there but I think I think
we're moving towards it and I really
think that whole concept of it
customized automation to the hacker um
will become will become huge yeah yeah
for sure um on that topic another one
that I would love to see is like hack
verter type for kaido um yeah dude okay
so that actually is going to be native
and introduced like next week so
definitely by the time this episode airs
um that will be that will be released
and essentially how it's going to work
is um there's going to be you know
there's this whole concept of convert
workflows in kaido right you select some
range of btes or whatever right and it
pipes it into a workflow where you can
do all sorts of stuff manipulate it
encode it decode it run run JavaScript
on it you know all that sort of thing
and then essentially that is going to be
integrated right into the replay tab
which is the the kaido equivalent of
repeater in um in kaido um and so
essentially like we use uh you know how
like in Intruder and in automate you
like select a little region where you're
going to start brute forcing y so yeah
with those little like marker things
yeah with a little marker things so
we're gonna have the same thing like
that in kaido where and it's already
built it just hasn't been released yet
where um you select a certain portion
and you select a convert workflow that
goes along with it and then when you
send that request it will automatically
dump it through that convert workflow
which is going to be absolutely massive
for um doing some more complicated
testing in an environment where like all
right now I've got to like take it and
URL encode it then base 64 encode it
then URL encode the Bas 64 you know like
and then convert all of the slashes to
dashes and like that sort of thing um
yeah I do love how modular the the like
workflow like ideology is um because you
can call other convert workflows from
convert workflows mean you can chain
them yeah yeah so that'll be but I think
the whole the whole concept is you know
around the the workflows is you have
these little nodes where you can do each
individualized pieces um along the way
in one convert workflow right yeah yeah
and the function kind of has extensions
in the same way as well yeah and so you
can write like encapsulated JavaScript
in one and then pass it to another one
and that sort of thing right yeah super
cool super cool yeah hack F hack F will
be great all right so let me let me tell
you about this one man and actually this
one's already implemented and this one
is already released to the critical
thinkers um on the Discord which by the
by the way there have been like 30 plus
people that have joined the critical
thinkers tier over the past like week so
dude this book this book he wrote is a
killer it's it's it's working man it's
flying off the
shelves best seller in the in the bug
Bounty World um no New York
Times top Digest 100 copies
so um no uh I really do appreciate that
all of you that have uh subscribed over
the past uh week uh it's amazing to see
so encouraging and thank you for all the
positive feedback about the uh the
full-time bug bnie blueprint that's been
amazing um so yeah shout shout out to
y'all but anyway the the extension that
I was going to talk about has already
been released to um the critical thinker
uh and essentially it's so have you ever
heard of um what is the name of it it's
like espan espand what is ESP yeah espo
espano espano I have heard of it wait is
that the one where you like type
something and it converts like what you
wrote into yes it's like a tool look
like a piece of software you install
right it's like a text expander right so
I use this all the time and all of my
stuff is in here it's amazing and you
showed me this and I think you're crazy
for using it by the way but but I love
you for it
it's just I don't know it's very like um
it's very like old school you know what
I mean yeah like I I'm I mean I
obviously I think we all use it in like
our own way like I use bash aliases like
it's you know that's like whatever but
this is like
Global calling me old school listen
listen I use I use autocorrect for this
okay speaking of old school I don't I
don't use any third party software I I I
create like an auto correct like
dictionary entry and
like my own custom like HT I use like
HTML coding format so I use like and and
then like a keyword and then semicolon
and then I'll type that and auto correct
will'll be like did you mean this you're
like yes I did well all right let me
explain to the people who don't even
know what this is so asenso is a text
expander so essentially I type um uh I
type colon
wh1 right and that automatically
replaces that colon wh1 with rhino at we
are hacker one right so whenever I'm
trying to like log into my my accounts
for testing and stuff like that I just
type col wh1 and it just populates my my
okay name yeah here's a weird question
yeah does it work on Android emulators
like through like if you're typing it
happens at the at the keyboard level um
so I think it does does it like
backspace to like yeah okay which is
pretty cool that might work yeah cuz
normally what I have to do is like I
copy something on my clipboard and then
I switch tabs like into the window and
it transfers the clipboard over and then
it's like kind of clunky but it works
yeah it works and that's actually try
and that's actually how I implement it
so anyway I took this concept and I was
like wow this is great um I want
something like this for my HTTP proxy
right because I'm constantly going
through and I'm like okay I've got like
Joel's organization ID and then Joel's
like account ID and then you know and
then I'm Justin's account ID Joel you
know J's organization ID and you've got
all these IDs and all these like
payloads and stuff like that you got to
keep track of and so what you do is is I
built a plugin where you just
essentially hit highlight some text hit
a keyboard binding and give it a name
and now uh you can access that that text
that was selected uh in the replay tab
in any any interface in kaido by just
typing like squiggly line and then the
name you gave it and it automatically
Backspaces the stuff you wrote and then
inserts the the stuff that you you had
selected in the beginning does it use uh
asando for this or is this like a fully
within kaid this is native to kaido I
just wrote it in JavaScript and it was
really
easy so it's like globally anywhere or
is it
just what yeah anywhere anywhere inside
the kaido interface because kaido's
front end is all JavaScript right so
okay you know I just wrote a front end
plugin that that just looks for
selection and waits for this key binding
and then when you hit it it pops up an
alert box say great you selected the
text abc123 what do you want to name it
and you just type like a or whatever and
then any type time you type uh whatever
that squiggly line is Tilda um a then it
Backspaces a Backspaces Tilda and
replaces it with
abc123 okay so you you got me thinking
here because yeah I'm using my brain
again uh oh uh oh okay so um I used to
so I still do this sometimes when I'm
testing a really complex API sometimes I
will go through the effort of writing it
out into like paw or um insomnia or um
Postman or whatever and I'll I'll
actually structure out the API and I'll
build out like parts of it especially if
it's something that like for instance
ooth 2 signing major pain in the ass to
do testing on so if you use like a rest
client often times it'll do the signing
and it'll update the header and stuff
automatically maybe that would be a good
K of pluging in of itself but absolutely
um the point is for like really complex
API testing um one of the really nice
features I like about these rest clients
is they have like the concept of
environments right so you have like an
environment with different variables and
each of those environments you can
switch between the environments you can
Define variables and then you can use
those variables throughout your project
and you can change them in one place so
like like you said like user ID for
example like Justin user ID and Joel's
user ID if I want to do cross account
testing I could create two variables
like account one ID account two ID and
then you could just swap that in easily
in different parts I don't know wow if
you could do that with plugins but it
would be really cool to have some sort
of like environment Plugin or variables
plugin where you could Define different
variables then you could use those
throughout like in your replay tab um or
wherever you're trying to do testing and
then you could change them in one place
or you could just have them written down
because I find that a lot of the time
when I'm doing testing especially with
cross account testing for idors and
stuff I just have to like write it down
in my notes and just like put it at the
top of the note and just keep it there
cuz I don't really have a really good
way of doing that sort of testing other
than that um and having it defined
within the proxy would be really neat
yeah absolutely and and and that solves
that whole problem of like okay you're
session died and now all of your your
repeater tabs or your replay tabs or
whatever are are dead and now you've got
to like copy the the cookie in you know
15 bajillion times right until you know
it until you've repopulated all your
requests and that sort of thing right
well and I think it's like one nicer
step up from ex your your expand thing
as well because it again like you can
update it in one place so if your
account gets banned and you have to
create a new one and you want to change
that all of your expand a text that's
like just like static within the the
request but this would like reference
like a variable so to speak and then you
could just like change it in one place
and it would all of them would still
update dynamically yeah no I like that I
like that a lot and I think that's
something that um this exact concept is
something we've discussed uh with the
kaido team of creating this sort of like
Global variable of sorts that you can
use uh you know in automate and replay
and that sort of thing and I would love
to see burp Implement something like
this too because at the end of the day
um something like this should absolutely
exist already uh and it's kind of odd
that it that it doesn't um and it should
be pretty easy to do I know that with um
you know with these uh convert workflows
in kaido you could sort of hack
something like this together where you
create a convert workflow that's named
like Joel's session returns a string and
yeah exactly and so you could sort of
hack this together but I like the idea
more more so of having like a front-end
environment drop down or whatever that
you can select when you before you
submit a request or like maybe it'll be
like on the send button for for replay
or repeater it'll have like the send
button and then like a little drop down
arrow or whatever right where you click
that and you say send with uh Joel's
environment send with just well you
think about how this could apply to like
sessions for example like that plugin
that updates your session in replay well
instead you take a request you highlight
your session and you right click and you
say you know assign to variable session
or update variable session and then all
of your requests instead of having a
static cookie they're referencing the
variable called session and again it all
updates from one place so you know you
can dynamically update your requests you
don't have to have long cookies or
whatever in every single request you
just have it reference like session
variable and you know absolutely that's
big man that's big I like that I would
love to see that I think that one might
take the cake so far I mean I think my
Expo tool um like the reason I wrote it
it's like a good vzero you know yeah
it's a good vzero and it's like solves a
scratches an itch that I had in the
situation and and it got me um a little
bit deeper into the the kaido sort of
front end plugin environment which I
really really liked but I think there is
a lot of room for improvement there and
I think if you were to use something if
they were to implement something
natively like um environments and
variables and that sort of thing then um
then that would be massive and a lot of
this would become irrelevant then um
yeah so no that's really interesting
though um anyway so regarding that
plugin until that this environment thing
comes out um that plugin I think I'm
going to release to the public around
Defcon time so depending it's already
released to critical thinkers right it
is it's already released to the critical
thinkers um exclusive content channel so
if you're interested in that check out
um check out ctbb doow
SLP Discord I should probably actually
make SLP Discord yeah because it's like
if you do slash SL Discord then it it
just takes you right to the Discord
invite leak maybe maybe I'll make like
uh ctbb
doow
cers right critical thinkers no
cers there's a whole conversation that
was happening in the Discord that's like
we need a better name for us than CT RS
like cers yeah we're all from
Connecticut yeah we're all like C tier
hackers we're all C tier hackers yeah uh
oh critical thinkers SL critical think
all right I'm just going to make that
I'm ctvb doow critical thinkers if you
want to get to that environment all
right Joel come on um all right you you
want to take one or should I take one
[Music]
uh hold on I'm just reading through I'm
reading through I'm reading through um
yeah so this this trace this Trace
cookies one is really interesting I
don't know if you have more information
than what's written down here but um Let
me let me just spin off it for a second
so um I mean based on what it sounds
like it seems you know basically just
tracing cookies right so so um I find
this really interesting when you're
trying to figure out like how log and
flows work and like what's necessary
what's not necessary we've talked about
this a lot with like cookies and I'm
constantly haunted by whether or not I
should be removing my cookies or not
because of that one Zoom atto with the
I'm like I'm like uh I'm probably just
missing an entire category of bug um but
that being said being able to trace
stuff and figure out like what stuff to
be looking at I I find this to be a
really interesting category as a whole
and I find myself more and more writing
like long filters and stuff in my in my
kaido um to really narrow down what I'm
seeing in my proxy so I can focus in on
stuff that matters yeah um so like CSS
files are really cool but I don't give a
crap about about them at all you know
what I mean like maybe maybe at some
point I will care you know what I mean
but like uh most of the time I don't um
so and the one thing about kaido super
nice is everything's recorded regardless
right like um with burp if you have I
mean the way that I have it configured
is when I put stuff in like the scope or
whatever it like completely ignores it
from the proxy so if there's stuff in
the past that may have not matched your
current scope rules or proxying rules or
filters or whatever then it's completely
gone for good you will never know but
with kaido you can bring that back so
maybe later if I'm looking for CSS then
I can you know find it yeah the way the
way I used to configure burp as well is
like that and the reason why and then I
stopped doing that once I got this like
server that I'm I'm on right now that
I'm recording this podcast on right now
because you know essentially you have to
put stuff that's not in your scope uh
don't like don't record it in burp or
else it'll just blow everything up and
you're just you're going to be you know
have 30 gigs of Google searches exactly
exactly but I think you can afford to
not do in kaido which is great um and
and it does allow you to have that sort
of retrospective you can go back and say
ah you know actually I really need to
know every S3 bucket that's ever been
referenced by this site you know you can
do that sort of thing um also well
really quick I find the big thing for me
is that I will at some point during my
hacking find a domain that either wasn't
in my like search or in my scope
properly or that I didn't know about and
I'll need to add it later and all the
previous requests I now have instead of
just like being a completely blank slate
and trying to figure out where that's
used um from then on yeah I I dig that
too but but what I was going to say with
regards to the trace cookie thing is
like here's here's my vision for this
like I want to be able to select a
cookie and say like give me a history of
this cookie and this cookie was like set
in this request and reset in this
request like the uh like the follow um
like uh Trace uh in wire shark how you
can like follow a packet yeah trace
route is that kind of what you're oh
well no no no not no in wi shark you can
yeah Trace stream how you can basically
like put together a series of TCP pack
stream yeah that's it yeah yeah so like
something like that is that what you're
exactly and and it's a little bit tricky
because you don't know whether it's
being you don't have a great way without
resending every request with every
single permutation of cookie to to
determine whether a specific request
needed a cookie or not right um so it's
a little bit tricky to know what
requests exactly needed what cookie um
but what I would say is if but you could
definitely trace the updates right like
yeah where it's being used is just like
I mean generally speaking if it's being
sent in the requests whether or not it's
needed I think cookies are like so broad
as a whole that it's really difficult
unless you have like again like a
separate there is that plugin for burp
um that minim request minimizer
minimizer yeah yeah yeah that does um
that basically does that but I think at
least the setting part of like following
where it's being set where it's being
updated that you could definitely do
pretty easily just based on the server
responses and where you have a set
cookie header being being returned yeah
so I think creating some sort of mapping
uh you know following the lifespan of a
cookie would be really interesting and
then also take looking at a cookie and
saying okay um where when is this value
found in the response ever and just kind
of tracing those things as well um and
then maybe even uh integrating so this
kind of goes down to what I was talking
about a little bit later in this
document which is it would be really
great to have something that seamlessly
hooks into the front end uh in in both
kaido and burp and and and um uh Domin
Vader sort of does this with with burp
uh but I think there's and I'm not a
Domin Vader Master by by any stretch but
I think there's some some things to be
improved upon in that Arena and and I
think this could be a really cool one
which is if there is some way for us to
determine whether uh document.cookie is
being accessed and then parsed and then
this specific cookie is being utilized
by the front end uh at a specific page
um and Trace back that JavaScript
execution that would be also a really
valuable piece of this whole whole like
Trace cookie profile that we would build
um and and man this s sort of
introspection would just breed the
coolest bugs ever because that's one of
the things that's like getting my goat
right now is I don't have enough
introspection into when a a front-end
application is looking for a cookie and
not finding it um looking for a cookie
finding it and doing something that I
don't know about looking for a query
parameter and not finding it you know
and that sort of thing so I need to do
more Dom hooking to actually understand
what's actually happening at the
application Level and I want to create
some sort of heads up display in the
browser just like maybe like I'm
thinking like a marquee you know toolbar
across the top of the browser or like
maybe in kaido natively or something
like that where it says um this page
that you're on uh looked for these eight
uh query parameters uh and we know this
because we hooked URL search parameters
or something like that right uh that
that that tool for parsing out query
parameters um so yeah I guess that's my
rant I would love more introspection
into that yeah yeah and I think it's
really interesting I mean I think both
kaido and burp have like BR their own
like browser integration type thing
where you can launch a browser and it
like Auto proxies or whatever I honestly
can I've had so much trouble like
getting behind that just because like
I'm very used to like you know my
certain flows or whatever extensions and
stuff that I have set up yeah exactly
exactly yeah so I don't really like
doing that that being said one thing
that I've done and I don't know if a lot
of people do this is bir burp the only
way that I know that you can use
dominador is if you use the burp
built-in browser right but if you look
in the way that it works it actually
loads uh like a Dev extension from like
a specific folder you could do that I I
use Chrome uh as my testing browser so I
just in my profile I you know enable Dev
and I load it from the same folder in My
Own Chrome instance so that I can
continue my testing and I can also use
Domin Vader still um and it works fine I
think like half the tool doesn't work
properly because it's not like hooked in
but yeah it's
um I'm I would imagine that kaido could
probably do something similar there or
you know verp two where you could have
um you know an extension that you can
point your browser to load and that will
interface with your proxy at a more deep
level where you could do that type of
stuff where you're talking about like
interfacing with the front end and
checking for variables and query
parameters and hooking and just wrapping
around like all those different types of
things yeah someday man I I'm really
looking forward to that because I think
there's so much as I start to understand
the web environment a little bit better
and I and I start understanding like hey
these individual top level Pages have so
much more encapsulated in them than what
comes through the HTTP proxy in modern
day web apps because of JavaScript and
just how much stuff JavaScript does in
so many different spots and it's not
like you can just look at one spot and
be like this is what it does or this is
what it doesn't do you know there's like
all sorts of middle wear throughout this
whole flow um and so tracing that out
would be would be massive and definitely
some some uh some massive challenge I
think that'd be really cool um and and
while we're on the on the cookie front
let me just talk about this next one
really quick so I have in in the in the
doc here setting cookies that you're not
responsible for so I saw this the other
day and I and it's like a pretty it's
like an informative thing like it's not
it doesn't indicate own or anything but
I saw a a website you know let's call
ity
setting a cookie where the domain was
scoped for like backend. site- dev.com
right you know and it's like and that
that was in the domain attribute for the
cookie and I was like hm that's a little
interesting uh and you know you hear
people talking about like look at the
CSP headers like Brute Force for V hosts
that sort of thing and this is another
area where you can find internal host
names that correlate to your application
that you may be able to use in other
areas is um if it's setting a cookie
that it's not authoritative for on the
specific domain yeah that's super
interesting I wonder if they just did
that for like the ease of developer
testing or something so that it it works
on the developers SLG it's a bug I mean
it wasn't an important cookie and and
that was the the name of the backend
server and it just like defaulted to
whatever it perceived its own host name
to be um cool so but yeah I thought that
was I thought that was really
interesting that it's very interesting
um one thing that you that you put in
here but I also expanded on um
highlighting or Bolding uh basic C4
encoded values so I think that would be
really neat if it just automatically
sort of showed you that you know this
thing is BAS 64 encoded um that's
probably a little hard to do accurately
I think uh if you just think about like
writing a Rex that can properly and
accurately or any way of you know just
generically saying well this is BAS 64
as a human we can like eyeball that so
much easier uh honestly um but uh that
being said so you can highlight values
and it'll try and auto decode it um in
both kaido and burp I'd love to see some
expansibility for that where we could
you know write your own decoder or maybe
there's some custom value or encryption
that the application's using and you
could just like double click on it and
you could you know specify that you want
to use your own custom decoder instead
and again just pipe this through
workflows or something um and you know
just be able to do some extra easier
custom decoding without having to
constantly like right click or pop
something up or whatever yeah so because
currently in in kaido to do that you
have to select then right click go to
the convert workflow and click it so
it's like three three clicks if you're
going through that whole thing well and
you could see how this could also be
awesome with like match and replace
rules as well if you could do that where
you could just do a match and replace
rule to call a workflow and just say
like okay if this matches like select
this Rex and
then that's exactly what I want them to
do too is like convert workflows and
match and replace would be super cool um
and then you just def like a Rex on the
front end and then like a convert
workflow to actually like pipe through
it I think that would be really amazing
so I think that one's on the on the on
the list as well but what I kind of
wanted to see with the Bas 624 encoded
values was um in burp there are some
extensions that will be like hey this
thing is b64 encoded just FYI right and
then here's the value I I think that
might be even like built into burp by
default or whatever um instead of
putting that in my findings tab I would
for that like B 64 encoded string to be
like underlined or in a different color
or like yeah where you hover over it
have some little tool tip or something
like that that draws my attention to it
because I'm very rarely when I use burp
going into the findings Tab and being
like all right let me just like check
out what's in the informative section
you know like it's always when you're
when you're having some problem and then
at like 3 hours later you go and you
check your answer has been sitting there
and you're like oh exactly exactly I
didn't have the certificate and Stu
exactly so it's it I think there's some
room for improvement there as far as
usability goes because there are some
detectors but having it underlined or
like having a little tool tip on it
would be really good um yeah all right
let's see G I see you wrote GPT
integration but I this already exists
this like they were early on the train
they were they were and I and I think
that there's cool stuff that you can do
with assistant uh in kaido right uh
and I think that's great I think there's
room for improvement the reason I say
this is because I've recently started
using co-pilot and co-pilot
is
unbelievable like absolutely
unbelievable uh in vs code right where
where you're trying to write some code
and you just like write a comment that
says like write this function that
reverses the string and exor it and then
you know and and then all of a sudden it
just boom it's there and and I just wow
like how stunning is that and and I
think there's lots of ways that we could
integrate this into
um into kaido or to burp that would be
really like friction reducing so you
know I'm trying to write out this whole
syntax uh I can just select the code you
know this whole bunch and say do make
this modification to it you know encode
every slash with uh you know uh w en
coding and just typee that out and then
the AI just does it or like um one area
that I said and actually um we've kind
of shouted this out a couple times
there's actually a kaido plugin for this
now um surrounding actually Auto
renaming yeah it's called AI replay uh
rename by riddle um like renaming your
tabs in in Replay in kaido uh based off
of in using AI to do that to make an
intuitive name so like oh this is the
get request for this endpoint uh that
gets the user information you know does
that use the buil-in does it use the
assistant like backend built in kaido to
do all that okay yeah so there's like a
certain number of like token counts you
get if you're a kaido pro user or
whatever um yeah but I just think after
using uh the co-pilot and just being
able to like select a bunch of text and
then say like fix bug and then just
describe what I wanted to change and
then have it do it I just like wow we
need this in an hgp Pro
yeah yeah and I think the big thing
would be if they could figure out how to
make some sort of assistant that is
specifically geared towards that and
trained on that type of data like one of
the reasons that copilot is so good at
code is that it's specifically geared
towards writing code so it's really
really good at that and like chat gbt
can write code
sometimes depends on what it's doing um
think you know yeah it's pretty good but
you know a lot of the time well some of
the time it definitely will miss um
because that's not really what it's you
know designed for whereas co-pilot is
like trained on you know GitHub and
stack Overflow data and all that kind of
stuff so it's like very very
specifically designed to write code yeah
okay I I agree and and and and I want to
say that in addition to that I think
this is one of the few areas where it's
like I wouldn't really say to the burp
team or to the kaido team like hey you
should implement this natively like I
think this is something that I would
actually pay for as a plugin like
there's very few plugins that I would
like shell out cash for I don't know why
that is because I'm sure some plugins
would make me tons of Roi uh but like I
don't know it's just a now that I'm
saying it it sounds it sounds dumb but
uh but you know like you've got JS
weasel right which is a you know an
Enterprise product for assessing JS code
right I think defin I haven't purchased
it yet but I think very soon when it
meets the capabilities that I'm looking
for that will be a buy and I think this
could also be a buy where it's like oh
there's a really really really high
quality um AI plugin for burp and for
kaido um and this is a startup and it
costs $30 a month if you want to use it
or $50 a month or whatever and it just
reduces friction left and right in your
HTTP proxy and allows you to just
describe what you want and it just does
it you know um I think that I think that
could be a really amazing
product super interesting maybe you
shouldn't have said that on the podcast
you know I'm here to add value I'm here
to please take my startup idea and do
something with it I would love that all
right man um I got to bounce uh there
are a couple more ideas in
here maybe I'll be late to this next
meeting are there any that you all right
I'll tell you what pick your top two
because there is one I I still wanted to
talk about okay um and or so how about
this pick your top one and I'll talk
about this one so um the one that I'd
mentioned you you mentioned that um I
think you said uh Haku piku was talking
about um you know how this this uh this
functionality that Gareth had identified
was really good for a stuff well I was
thinking like right off the bat I was
like well there should be a ooth testing
plugin and then I looked through the
list and on the list it says something
for attacking ooth specifically and then
there's a link to this burp plugin
called oh scan that it does exactly this
so yeah this is another one of those
ones that I mentioned that um is
probably just a direct Port I don't know
if this one's going to be so easy it
looks like it's written in Java and it's
like pretty in depth um and it does like
a lot of different tests and stuff but
this would be another one of those great
ones to Port over and get working in
kaido and in addition to that maybe add
this functionality customize it a little
bit like you said to add in this
additional scan uh for this additional
um you know Bypass or whatever you want
to call it that Gareth described
Behavior yeah no I and I think I think
it's great that they have all these all
these you know extensions already in
burp and I
think you know it's just one of those
scenarios where it's like wow there's so
many pieces that I don't know about
right so many so many extension code you
know pieces of extension code that I
don't know how they work and I should
probably just Deep dive in and learn how
to use it efficiently or whatever or I
could just write my own cuz I have to
know I have to have that gut sense
anyway as the hacker like this is
actually goes goes to a pretty a pretty
big hacker topic because I've always
wondered like what makes hackers so
Scrappy like why don't we just want to
pay for something or why don't we want
to just use these tools why do we want
to reinvent the wheel every time and I
think the reason for that is because we
need to know what is happening you know
at a low level so that we can feed that
gut and that intuition of
like this feels like something I should
apply this tool to you know
um so I don't know I'm sure there's more
to sus out there but um okay let me let
me let me just I'm I'm going to do two I
got to go like like two minutes but I'm
going to try to cover two more two more
extensions really quickly okay one is I
would like some extension that allows
you to specify where an API lives and
then um make sure that you have 100%
coverage of that API so let's say I give
it a path I say okay all the stuff for
um you know epic games lives under epic
games.com
right and essentially I want to see in
my HTP history if there is a API
endpoint that I'm missing that I haven't
sent to repeater or haven't marked as
like boring I want that like glowing in
my hgp history you know okay yeah so so
like coverage like a reverse Target
where like in burp you can have like
your target of like things that are
under domains of endpoints that belong
to that domain but instead you say
here's all of the end points that exist
and it would say okay here's a request
for every single one of these and then
highlight the ones that don't have a
request yeah well absolutely that but
also when a new one comes through and
this is like you know one that I haven't
sent to replay or I haven't marked as
boring I want that like glowing in my
hgp history like hey there's this new
one that you haven't seen that you know
got bundled in with the 40 other request
that happen when you went to this page
yeah so like marking a uh endpoints as
like process or scene basically as well
within the scope so that when something
new comes up that you know you can mark
all As Seen but then you can yeah I like
so that I can be sure that I have
coverage of all of these API end points
and I understand every single freaking
thing about this application cool okay
and then next one sorry last one is that
man there is why is there not good note
taking in either kaido or burp like how
cool would it be to be able to write
notes and like reference um tab numbers
and like bro there's this there's this
notes uh organizer thing whatever in
burp I've tried to use it I can't even
tell you how many times uh more than 10
it's never worked never I clicked the
button nothing happens I I gave up yeah
so it's like I I just feel like this is
something that should be super pivotal
and instead we all have like notes. as
you know uh a.txt or whatever uh
notes.txt and that we all just kind of
dump stuff into um but man it would be
really really helpful to be able to like
apply a note to a specific path rejects
or like apply a note to a specific um
request uh or just lots of functionality
they should be built out surrounding
that um all right cool that's it I got
to run but notes please please somebody
build that notes at at least notes yeah
exactly all right man good pod cool
peace all catch you later
peace and that's a wrap on this episode
of critical thinking thanks so much for
listening and if you want more critical
thinking content head over to ctbb show/
Discord join the Discord there's lots of
great conversations and chats going on
over there and if you want to support
the show there's the Discord subscriber
tiers which give you access to master
classes amas hack along alongs exclusive
scripts and an exclusive chat Channel
with us we'll see you there